<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>〉streetdogg _</title>
        <link>https://streetdogg.in/</link>
        <description>Recent content on 〉streetdogg _</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Piyush Itankar</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 18:58:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://streetdogg.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Piyush Itankar</title>
        <link>https://streetdogg.in/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 18:58:29 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://streetdogg.in/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who has a why can bear almost any how!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By profession, I am an Embedded Systems, Software Engineer. I am passionate about studying electricity and use that as a way to understand the world around me. How we can make inanimate matter do our bidding is something that has always fascinated me and leaves me in awe every time I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other intellectual interests are in the fields of - Humanities, Psychology and Human behavior, Justice, and Education. It&amp;rsquo;s just amazing how far humanity has come and how much it has achieved. I like to ponder on how all of it happened, despite catastrophic events like the World Wars!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have gone OCD on studying the interaction between Waves and Matter, and Mathematical Modeling of Biological Systems. It may not seem obvious but both these topics have given me a very different view of how Nature operates! Here is a snap of the books I am in love with -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Blog is a collection of notes. These notes include experiences, comments on career development, experiments in Embedded systems development, and random other things that I feel like keeping a record of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use writing as a way to slow down my thinking. Usually, the intention is to grab something of worth, something that helps me improve as a human, learn more about how I and the world operate together, or (mostly) a way to correct my model of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you find these helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by, &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Piyush Itankar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chuck it, Let’s do it!</title>
        <link>https://streetdogg.in/p/chuck-it-lets-do-it/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 16:15:12 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://streetdogg.in/p/chuck-it-lets-do-it/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first thing I realized after landing on the spongy bed was -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s usually we who stand in our own way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winning is more a matter of choice and will than practice, training and genius. You either choose to win or the devil’s advocate in you convinces you to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no clue, even today what had made me sign up for the High Jump. Sure I was called the monkey by my mates usually, but jumping 5ft is not my cup of tea. Truth be told, when I looked at the beam (which I was supposed to jump over) placed 3.5ft high, I was wondering how can anyone jump over it. It was paralyzing me mentally. I was convinced that it was hard, it was impossible. Except something inside me said,” It’s ok to screw up. Go jump!” I took a step back, ran, gathered the momentum and with all my might launched into the air. Over the next fraction of a second, I was on the other side of the beam. I had made it. I had done what a while ago seemed impossible. I ended up jumping as high as 4 point something feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing things happened when I was in mid-air. While in flight. I had surrendered myself. My mind had stopped talking. I couldn’t hear anything. The world around had paused. Eyes were open yet I could see nothing. I had surrendered myself to whatever would happen. Covered with a sense of peace, contentment and stillness. A state, we all in the modern world crave for. I never knew that side of me existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing is clear though, I don’t know what brings happiness but contentment comes with Micro-Achievements. Daily small wins!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
